Guide to the Blackstone Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Blackstone family papers
1705-1844
MS 916
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
Chiefly deeds, estate papers and financial records of the Blackstone family of Branford, Connecticut. Included also are two farm account books for the years 1772-1839 and that of David Welles, Jr. for the years 1773-1786. Among the Branford papers is a Grand Jury presentment against two men for disloyal acts during the Revolution.
Blackstone family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Mrs. Hope Collins, 1953.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Legal and financial papers pertaining largely to the Blackstone family and the town of Branford, Connecticut, make up this small collection.
Members of the Blackstone family represented here are John Blackstone, Sr. (died 1818), his wife, Hannah Harrison (died 1815), and son John, Jr., and Stephen Blackstone (died 1807), brother of John, Sr., and his wife, Ann. Papers include a farm account book with receipts and other loose papers laid in, a deed, and estate papers. Papers pertaining to the town of Branford include deeds, receipts, and estate papers; a Grand Jury presentment summoning two men to answer the charge that they concealed "knowledge of a Number of Persons endeavoring to Joine the Enemies of this, & the rest of the United States," signed by Gideon Bartholomew (1782); an assessors' list of polls and estates; a certificate appointing surveyors of highways; and letters pertaining to the appointment of William Russell to the town's Democratic Confidential Committee.
The final item in the collection is a farm account book with notes and other loose papers laid in, belonging to David Welles, Jr. (1750-1816), of Shelbourne, Massachusetts. It is unclear whether Welles was connected to the Blackstone family.
Agriculture -- Accounting; Families; Branford (Conn.); Connecticut; United States -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; Deeds; Farmers; Blackstone, Hannah, d. 1815; Blackstone, John, d. 1818; Blackstone, John; Blackstone, Stephen, d. 1807; Welles, David, 1750-1816; Blackstone family
- Inventory
  - Blackstone family
    - John Blackstone, Jr.: farm account book, 1772-1839 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Stephen Blackstone
      - Deed with Ann Blackstone to John Blackstone, 1801 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Estate papers, [1807] (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hannah (Harrison) Blackstone: estate papers, [1815] (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - John Blackstone, Sr.: estate papers, [1818] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Branford, Connecticut
    - Deeds, estate papers, and receipts, 1705/6-1837 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Grand jury presentment to Elias Pond and Abraham Rogers, 1782 November 6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Assessors' list of quantity and valuation of polls and different kinds of estate, 1814 August 20 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Certificate of appointment of surveyors of highways, 1837 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - William Russell: letters related to his appointment to the Democratic Confidential Town Committee for Branford, 1844 January-February (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - David Welles, Jr.: farm account book and notes, 1773-1786 (Box 1, Folder 10)